<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Thoughts and Stuff</title>
    <description>Thoughts and Stuff is a place for me to get my thoughts about Apple and tech in general out of my head. Occasionally, I might write about travel, education, or football, too. 
</description>
    <link>http://thoughtsandstuff.net/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://thoughtsandstuff.net/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2019 02:32:53 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2019 02:32:53 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.3.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Shortcut for keeping 8-Ball Scores</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Editor’s note: This post is an updated version of the original post that I wrote for the previous Workflow. It reflects changes made to allow removing opponents, renaming Workflow to Shortcuts, and a few more minor improvements. You can still view the original post &lt;a href=&quot;/pool-scores-old&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d wager that &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/gamepigeon/id1124197642?mt=8&amp;amp;uo=4&amp;amp;at=10l6nh&quot;&gt;GamePigeon&lt;/a&gt;’s 8-Ball is the most used iMessage app out there. It feels like everyone (myself included) plays it. But how does go about keeping score?&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; I used to type the score after every game but after forgetting / losing track a couple of times, I decided to build a &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/shortcuts/id915249334?mt=8&amp;amp;uo=4&amp;amp;at=10l6nh&quot;&gt;shortcut&lt;/a&gt; to semi-automate the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;getting-started&quot;&gt;Getting started&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other than the &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/gamepigeon/id1124197642?mt=8&amp;amp;uo=4&amp;amp;at=10l6nh&quot;&gt;GamePigeon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/shortcuts/id915249334?mt=8&amp;amp;uo=4&amp;amp;at=10l6nh&quot;&gt;Shortcuts&lt;/a&gt; apps (both free on the App Store), you’ll need both of the following shortcuts: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.icloud.com/shortcuts/e93ab2d6999f4255a38687e393a7a1de&quot;&gt;Manage Pool Opponents&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.icloud.com/shortcuts/9c2fd5ae46394b9686abf041911fb09b&quot;&gt;Pool Scores&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing you do is run &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Manage Pool Opponents&lt;/code&gt;, which is a Normal shortcut (it only shows up in the Shortcuts app, not the widget). It’ll ask for your name the first time you run it, and to set a file name&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. The shortcut will then ask if you would like to ‘Add an opponent’ or ‘Remove an opponent’. Choose the former, enter the name of your opponent, and choose if you want to initialize scores. If you say yes, you can set the score to what your current scores are. If not, it’ll set the score to 0-0. Repeat this for each of your opponents. It’ll save your scores as &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;'Pool Scores'&lt;/code&gt; in Shortcuts’ iCloud Drive directory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, run &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Pool Scores&lt;/code&gt; and enter your name &lt;strong&gt;exactly as you did above&lt;/strong&gt;. It’ll grab the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;'Pool Scores'&lt;/code&gt; dictionary file and ask you to select a name from your list of opponents, and then ask if you won, lost, or just want to get the score. If you choose won or lost, it’ll update the score accordingly and then get the score (it both displays the score and copies it to clipboard in case you want to send it to your opponent).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Pool Scores&lt;/code&gt; shortcut is a Today Widget (and Apple Watch) shortcut so after every game, you can just swipe down to bring up Notification Center and update scores from there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read on below for a more detailed documentation of how the shortcuts work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-does-it-work-documentation&quot;&gt;How does it work? (Documentation)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each shortcut has two Import Questions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Enter your name here. Expected input is text &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;myname&lt;/code&gt; with no white-space (e.g. Karan), but anything works (so long as you enter it exactly the same in both shortcuts).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What would you like the file to be saved as in iCloud Drive? Both shortcuts rely on a dictionary file in Shortcut’s iCloud Drive directory. By default, this is read and written as &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Pool Scores.json&lt;/code&gt; but you can change it to whatever you like here - just make sure that you change it in both shortcuts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;manage-pool-opponents&quot;&gt;Manage Pool Opponents&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is where you initially create the dictionary, and where you can add or remove opponents. It either adds or updates key-value pairs in an existing dictionary, or it creates a new dictionary with the given key-value pair. It works as follows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Add an opponent:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The shortcut asks for your opponent’s name. Expected input is text &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;opponentname&lt;/code&gt; with no white-space (e.g. James), but anything works.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The shortcut asks if you want to initialize scores. If yes, expected input is number. Enter your score and your opponent’s score where prompted. If no, scores are assigned as 0-0.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The shortcut gets the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Pool Scores&lt;/code&gt; dictionary file from Shortcuts’ iCloud Drive directory, and gets the dictionary from the file. If the file doesn’t exist (for example, if you’re running the shortcut for the first time) it’ll be created later.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The shortcut sets the dictionary value for you and for your opponent. It does this with keys &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;mynameopponentname&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;opponentname&lt;/code&gt;  with values &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;myscore&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;opponentscore&lt;/code&gt; respectively &lt;em&gt;(e.g. {“KaranJames”:100, “James”:0})&lt;/em&gt;. If these names already exist in the dictionary, they will be overwritten.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The shortcut saves the dictionary to the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Pool Scores&lt;/code&gt; file in Shortcuts’ iCloud Drive directory. If the file exists (for example, if you’re adding a new opponent or re-initializing scores) it’ll overwrite the file.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Remove an opponent:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The shortcut gets the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Pool Scores&lt;/code&gt; dictionary file from Shortcuts’ iCloud Drive directory. &lt;strong&gt;This file must already exist&lt;/strong&gt;, execution will end here otherwise.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The shortcut gets all keys from the dictionary file. Some of these will be in the form &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;opponentname&lt;/code&gt; while others will be in the form &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;mynameopponentname&lt;/code&gt;. We need to get rid of the latter to present a list of opponent names.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The shortcut splits these keys into new lines. It then finds all the keys that begin with &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;myname&lt;/code&gt; and replaces them with a blank. It then goes through and deletes all blank lines.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The shortcut presents this updated list of keys (opponent names) and asks you to pick one or more.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For each selected opponent, the shortcut will set both your scores to 0.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The shortcut will then remove your scores from the dictionary, and then clean itself up (for example: any leading or trailing commas in the dictionary will be removed).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The shortcut will finally ask you to confirm your changes. If you say yes, it will save the updated dictionary to iCloud Drive. If you cancel, execution will stop here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;pool-scores&quot;&gt;Pool Scores&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This shortcut grabs an existing dictionary (make sure you run the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Manage Pool Opponents&lt;/code&gt; shortcut at least once first to create one), asks you to choose from a list of your opponents, updates the score (if necessary), and copies/displays it. This shortcut is best used from the Today Widget (after first run). It works as follows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The shortcut gets the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Pool Scores&lt;/code&gt; dictionary file from Shortcuts’ iCloud Drive directory. &lt;strong&gt;This file must already exist&lt;/strong&gt;, execution will end here otherwise.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The shortcut gets all keys from the dictionary file. Some of these will be in the form &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;opponentname&lt;/code&gt; while others will be in the form &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;mynameopponentname&lt;/code&gt;. We need to get rid of the latter to present a list of opponent names.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The shortcut splits these keys into new lines. It then finds all the keys that begin with &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;myname&lt;/code&gt; and replaces them with a blank. It then goes through and deletes all blank lines.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The shortcut presents this updated list of keys (opponent names) and asks you to pick one.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The shortcut fetches the dictionary file again, getting just the key-value pairs for you and the opponent you selected this time, and stores the values in &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;My Score&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Opponent Score&lt;/code&gt; variables as appropriate (with the keys again being of the form &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;mynameopponentname&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;opponentname&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The shortcut asks you to choose from a menu: “I won”, “I lost”, or “Get score”. “I won” and “I lost” simply increment either the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;My Score&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Opponent Score&lt;/code&gt; variable as appropriate, and then jumps to “Get score”.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The shortcut fetches the dictionary file again. It sets (updates) the dictionary value for keys &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;mynameopponentname&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;opponentname&lt;/code&gt; with the updated score variables.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The shortcut saves the updated dictionary file, overwriting &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Pool Scores.json&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The shortcut copies &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;My Score - Opponent Score&lt;/code&gt; to clipboard, so you can share it with your opponent if you want.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The shortcut displays the text &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;MyName MyScore-OpponentScore OpponentName&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;The app keeps track of how many games you’ve won, but it doesn’t sync across devices (so iPhone and iPad keep different scores) and it doesn’t let you know your opponent’s score. I’ve also found the number to be inconsistent. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;I expect most people to leave this as the default. Truthfully, it only exists so that I can more easily test and debug when I add new features without messing with my canonical dictionary. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://thoughtsandstuff.net/pool-scores</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thoughtsandstuff.net/pool-scores</guid>
        
        
        <category>apple</category>
        
        <category>shortcuts</category>
        
        <category>gaming</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>IKEA RÄLLEN Review</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/rallen.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the tentpole features of the iPhones 8 and iPhone X this year has been the glass back and wireless charging. Apple elected to use the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Qi_(standard)&quot;&gt;Qi standard&lt;/a&gt;, which has been around for almost a decade, so there were lots of third-party accessories already available at launch. Apple has chosen to promote two: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/shop/product/HL802ZM/A/belkin-boost-up-wireless-charging-pad?fnode=3f587a7b73659997292babb4d9f94da8e69e3d8adceaaaf35fc2bdaaa7eb3ab849b99f87c550afe00cb0194c2d21e586870615e5806f91a855a2f41ffe0ebd731a3297eec26ac0138466f2991d809b935ee0ceb1480180951219d6415b3be85c&quot;&gt;Belkin&lt;/a&gt; (bad) and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/shop/product/HL812ZM/A/mophie-wireless-charging-base?fnode=3f587a7b73659997292babb4d9f94da8e69e3d8adceaaaf35fc2bdaaa7eb3ab849b99f87c550afe00cb0194c2d21e586870615e5806f91a855a2f41ffe0ebd731a3297eec26ac0138466f2991d809b935ee0ceb1480180951219d6415b3be85c&quot;&gt;Mophie&lt;/a&gt; (good). However, I decided to go a different route.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of people consider wireless charging as it exists today to be a gimmick. It’s slow and makes it hard to use your phone while charging. While that’s a very valid argument, I like to think about it from another angle: Magic Furniture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;hardware-and-installation&quot;&gt;Hardware and installation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I rented a Zipcar&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; just over a week ago and drove to IKEA. I picked up a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ikea.com/us/en/catalog/products/70232902/&quot;&gt;FIXA drill&lt;/a&gt; ($27), &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ikea.com/us/en/catalog/products/20302332/&quot;&gt;FIXA hole saw&lt;/a&gt; ($5), &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ikea.com/us/en/catalog/products/90318023/&quot;&gt;RÄLLEN&lt;/a&gt; ($12), and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ikea.com/au/en/catalog/products/70291878/&quot;&gt;JYSSEN&lt;/a&gt; ($29).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Installation was as simple as charging the drill, connecting the hole saw, and picking two pieces of furniture to put a hole through. I went with my nightstand and a side table I have by the couch. Once the hole is drilled, you drop the charger in from the top. There’s a ring around it to keep it stable and in place. The entire process took about 30 minutes for the two tables. That includes taking intermittent breaks for the drill to cool down, vacuuming the debris, and wiping the table before connecting the charger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I did buy both the RÄLLEN and JYSSEN, I’ve only used the latter a couple of times. It’s on a table that’s less accessible to me usually. I bought it because it was 40% off on a clearance sale. While it looks identical to the RÄLLEN at first glance, you can push down on the JYSSEN and it pops up to expose a hidden USB charger. That makes it a good option to have for guests (I often have friends over charging their phones in my room - this felt like a good solution for that). I set up the RÄLLEN on my nightstand and it’s the one I’ll focus on for the rest of the review.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have the IKEA &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ikea.com/au/en/catalog/products/90354068/&quot;&gt;BRIMNES&lt;/a&gt; bedside table. I elected to install the RÄLLEN on the shelf in the middle of the unit. The shelf slides out which makes installation super easy, and the back of the unit behind and underneath it is open, meaning that there are no exposed wires. It looks so seamless that I wouldn’t be surprised if IKEA started selling this as a set in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;using-the-rÄllen&quot;&gt;Using the RÄLLEN&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ‘sweet spot’ of this charger is fairly generous, as far as I can tell. I haven’t had to fiddle around to get it to start charging. I have the white charger which accents the table’s black wood quite nicely, and makes it somewhat visible in the dark, so I’ve had no issues setting my phone down on the pad late at night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve heard stories of some people having issues with their phones vibrating off wireless chargers at night - especially with the Belkin charger that Apple promotes. While this charger feels sufficiently grippy, I have ‘Vibrate on Silent’ turned off on my iPhone&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; (and Do Not Disturb scheduled while I sleep) so I can’t imagine this being an issue. Even with vibration turned off though, my phone still vibrates once it makes contact with the charger. This lets me set it down (often blindly in the dark) without having to worry that I missed the charger. There’s an ever-so-small LED indicator light on the RÄLLEN but it gets covered up by the resting iPhone, so I have no idea why it’s even there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My biggest reservation with picking this charger was the charging speed. As of writing, all of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ikea.com/us/en/catalog/categories/departments/wireless_charging/30611/&quot;&gt;IKEA’s wireless chargers&lt;/a&gt; have a max speed of 5W. The impending iOS 11.2 update is set to enable charging speeds of 7.5W and both the Belkin and Mophie chargers will support this. However, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.macstories.net/linked/testing-faster-wireless-charging-on-ios-11-2-beta/&quot; title=&quot;Permalink&quot;&gt;looking at early results in beta&lt;/a&gt;, the gains are negligible. I rarely charge my iPhone midday so having it charge a little slower while I sleep is fine. If I need to top up the battery quickly before heading out, having 7.5W (instead of 5W) isn’t going to make a difference. I’m still going to plug in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2017/11/3/16599178/iphone-x-8-plus-apple-fast-charging-usb-c-lighting-power-brick-cable-how-to&quot;&gt;29W iPad charger&lt;/a&gt; instead - I can get about 50% battery in 30 minutes with that charger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, one of my favorite things about the RÄLLEN is its design. Like I mentioned earlier: There’s a ring around the top of it that keeps it stable and in place. So to remove it, you just push it up from the bottom. This means that if IKEA decides to update the line with 7.5W charging, or if I decide to swap out the white charger for a black one, I can replace my current setup with ease.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-about-airpower&quot;&gt;What about AirPower?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apple briefly mentioned an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/iphone-8/#wireless-charging&quot;&gt;AirPower&lt;/a&gt; wireless charging mat alongside the new iPhones. We know nothing about the price or the release date (Apple says it’s “available in 2018”). What we do know is that it’ll charge an iPhone, Apple Watch, and AirPods simultaneously. Given that I charge all three of those devices bedside, and that I’m always looking to simplify my travel setup, I’m poised to pick up two of these. Yet this still hasn’t deterred me from going all-in on IKEA’s line of chargers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I, &lt;a href=&quot;http://atp.fm/episodes/248&quot; title=&quot;248: Chili Cookoff&quot;&gt;like John Siracusa&lt;/a&gt;, fully expect Apple to price AirPower at close to $200. I’ll still pick up one at launch at that price for my nightstand&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:3&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; but I can’t see myself littering my furniture with a plethora of AirPower mats. Yet that’s exactly what I want to do with wireless charging.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My goal is to have as much furniture as I can have an integrated charger. If I can  wire it so that the trailing cable is completely hidden, I will. I want magic furniture everywhere. Now that I’ve bought the drill and hole saw, &lt;strong&gt;each additional charger I buy will cost me $12&lt;/strong&gt;. That’s 40% less than the price of an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/shop/product/MD818AM/A/lightning-to-usb-cable-1-m&quot;&gt;Apple Lightning Cable&lt;/a&gt; alone, and 70% cheaper if you include the speed-equivalent &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/shop/product/MD810LL/A/apple-5w-usb-power-adapter?fnode=97&quot;&gt;5W USB Charger&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I might not need to charge my iPhone midday most days but I really like the idea of being able to naturally drop my iPhone down on a table and have it pick up a little extra charge. Best I can tell, the RÄLLEN seems to be the most frictionless way to do that — both in price and in practice.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:4&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:4&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;We don’t talk about &lt;a href=&quot;http://zipcar.com&quot;&gt;Zipcar&lt;/a&gt; enough. What a great service. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;If you have an Apple Watch, this seems like a no-brainer to me. If the notification is important, my Watch will notify me of it. If it’s not important, I don’t need to be distracted by it. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:3&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;That’s another reason why I installed the RÄLLEN in the middle shelf of the unit instead of on top; that’s where the AirPower mat will go. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:3&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:4&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;This should go without saying but none of this is relevant unless you have furniture that you’re comfortable drilling a hole through. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:4&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://thoughtsandstuff.net/ikea-rallen</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thoughtsandstuff.net/ikea-rallen</guid>
        
        
        <category>apple</category>
        
        <category>ikea</category>
        
        <category>charging</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Clips as a Photo Booth replacement</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I downloaded &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/clips/id1212699939?mt=8&amp;amp;uo=4&amp;amp;at=10l6nh&quot;&gt;Clips&lt;/a&gt; when &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.macstories.net/news/apple-launches-clips-video-app-for-iphone-and-ipad/&quot;&gt;it was released&lt;/a&gt; in April, but I genuinely can’t remember if I ever actually opened it. I’m sure I did at launch, and maybe again after &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.macstories.net/news/apples-clips-app-receives-update-adding-disneypixar-content-and-more/&quot;&gt;the big update&lt;/a&gt; in July, but this isn’t an app that I’ve spent a lot of time with. However, Clips 2.0 has been a little different. (This isn’t a review in any way. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.macstories.net/news/clips-20-introduces-selfie-scenes-for-iphone-x-star-wars-content-icloud-syncing-and-more/&quot;&gt;Check out MacStories&lt;/a&gt; first if you have no idea what Clips is.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the iPad 2, back in early 2011, &lt;a href=&quot;https://gizmodo.com/5774645/photo-booth-comes-to-ipad-only&quot;&gt;Apple brought Photo Booth to the iPad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. I distinctly remember thinking that this was a no-brainer at the time. Growing up in Ghana, there weren’t that many Macs in my high school, but everybody that had one used Photo Booth. It was very regular to walk into the sixth form (senior year) &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Common_room&quot;&gt;common room&lt;/a&gt; and see groups of friends, myself included, behind a MacBook playing with the filters. Talking to several of my American friends, it sounds like it was the same deal here&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. I always thought that it was only a matter of time before Apple brought Photo Booth to the iPhone, but six years later it still just ships with Macs and iPads (and I don’t think that it’s been updated in that time).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Playing with the Selfie Scenes in Clips last week, I had the same feeling that I did playing with Photo Booth on my Mac many years ago. It was a little surreal, as someone with incredible front-camera shyness, to find myself having so much fun with it. The whole experience had me thinking: In a few years, once the Face ID technology has spread to the rest of the iOS line (and maybe even the Mac), could Clips be the successor to Photo Booth? Between Selfie Scenes, stickers, Live Titles, and fast sharing to social media, it seems the perfect fit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I’m no longer young enough to know if &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/Hu8tX2BAD1k&quot;&gt;‘the yutes’&lt;/a&gt; are still using Photo Booth on their Macs (or iPads), I’m confident that they aren’t. This is the Snapchat generation and I think that it’ll take a lot to change that, especially since Selfie Scenes are tied exclusively to the iPhone X right now. Maybe Animoji in Clips could do it? All I know is that those few days with Clips took me &lt;em&gt;right back&lt;/em&gt; to senior year of high school. It’s just &lt;a href=&quot;https://thoughtsandstuff.net/iphone-x&quot;&gt;another example&lt;/a&gt; of how Apple is starting to delight again this year&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:3&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;This was back when Apple would release first-party apps on iOS to show off the power of the platform. I miss those days. More on that in a little bit. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;It’s actually a little uncanny, I had two people immediately respond with almost exactly what I said: Not a lot of Macs in high school, but groups of friends would find one and indulge. It was common to see Photo Booth pictures on Facebook and Tumblr. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:3&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;As &lt;em&gt;Myke Hurley&lt;/em&gt; posited on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.relay.fm/cortex/60&quot;&gt;the latest episode of Cortex&lt;/a&gt;, Apple’s year starts and ends with WWDC. We’re halfway through the year and it’s been a really good one so far. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:3&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://thoughtsandstuff.net/clips</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thoughtsandstuff.net/clips</guid>
        
        
        <category>apple</category>
        
        <category>clips</category>
        
        <category>ios</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Week with iPhone X</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/portland.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really didn’t want to write a first impressions post — there are &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.macstories.net/news/iphone-x-review-roundup/&quot;&gt;so many&lt;/a&gt; out there already — but I have a lot of thoughts about this phone, I had to share a few of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve had every iPhone since the iPhone 4, all relatively close to launch day (and all on launch day since the iPhone 5). I’m a nerd; I obsess over the details, the minutiae, and could go on for hours about the subtle (and not so subtle) differences between each generation. My friends, however, are not. For a few years now, I’ve had to fend the “so what’s new about it” questions. Not this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone knows about this phone. Even if they don’t know what’s new per se, they know that there’s a lot of hype around this it and they’re genuinely curious to find out why. Better yet, everyone loves it. It’s always something different: Some are drawn to Animoji, some to the OLED display, some to the camera. One of my friends’ fingerprints never worked with Touch ID, and he’s really looking forward to having a phone without it. It’s been a big hit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are always going to be those that still murmur “I can’t believe you spent $1,000 on a phone.” I always respond with “I actually spent almost $1,500 on it!”&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; It doesn’t go well. Some of them can still appreciate what the phone has to offer, others stop at the price tag. That’s fine. This is ‘the phone of the future,’ so they’ll get it one day. To me, this isn’t that much more than what I was already spending on my iPhone. I’ll pay the few hundred dollars premium to have the future today. Old iPhones still have good resale value, and the difference is worth it to me. &lt;strong&gt;Price is a touchy subject — everyone values things differently. Get it if you can, don’t get it if you can’t.&lt;/strong&gt; 🤷🏾‍♂️&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-design&quot;&gt;The design&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The physical design of this phone is fantastic. I went with the Space Gray model but it was really a coin toss between that and the Silver, which I got for my brother. They both look and feel incredibly premium. Yet for as much as I love the all-glass design, it gives me pause. During my seven years as an iPhone owner, the only one I’ve ever cracked (accidentally) is the back glass of the iPhone 4s — and I’ve never been one to use a case. This hasn’t been a problem in daily use but I felt a little uncomfortable taking it with me to the gym, so I bought the &lt;a href=&quot;https://store.apple.com/xc/product/MQTD2ZM/A&quot;&gt;Apple Leather Case&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. I owned this case briefly a few years ago with my iPhone 6 before selling it to a friend, and it’s been improved since, so I knew that I’d like it. I plan to use it when I go to the gym and when I travel, and to continue to use the phone without a case everywhere else. It’s worked well so far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next big design point is the notch. I don’t get the fuss around it at all. Sure, I would rather it not be there, but the tech to make that happen doesn’t exist yet. In terms of having the notch as-is (with the ‘ears’), or blacking it out and hiding it with software, I &lt;em&gt;much&lt;/em&gt; prefer having the ears. This phone truly feels all-screen — there’s no forehead. It wouldn’t feel that way with a ‘hidden’ notch. It doesn’t hide content, either&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:3&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Thanks to the true-black OLED display, watching video just looks as though you’re watching it on an iPhone 7. Not only is it not a big deal, but I’ve actually grown to enjoy the notch as a design element.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, I wanted to touch on app design. All but two of the apps on my home screen have been updated to support the iPhone X&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:4&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:4&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. That definitely makes this the easiest transition between major iPhone redesigns I’ve experienced yet. However, I would like to see developers do more with true-black dark modes on this phone. The OLED display really makes it look as though the screen is ‘off’ except for the interface elements that are ‘on.’ It’s hard to describe, but easy to demo. &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/ulysses/id1225571038?mt=8&amp;amp;uo=4&amp;amp;at=10l6nh&quot;&gt;Ulysses&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/reeder-3/id697846300?mt=8&amp;amp;uo=4&amp;amp;at=10l6nh&quot;&gt;Reeder&lt;/a&gt; have great dark modes that really show this off. Furthermore, I’d like to see more apps make it easier to switch between light and dark modes. I don’t like having dark mode always on — only really at night. &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/tweetbot-4-for-twitter/id1018355599?mt=8&amp;amp;uo=4&amp;amp;at=10l6nh&quot;&gt;Tweetbot&lt;/a&gt; makes this dead simple with a two-finger swipe gesture up or down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Better still, I’d love to see Apple take a swing at a native dark mode with iOS 12. Having it at the system level (maybe with a toggle in Control Center) with native dark mode APIs for developers to implement would be a dream, and frankly long overdue. It would probably have a decent impact on battery life, too.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:5&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:5&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;wireless-charging&quot;&gt;Wireless charging&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After doing some research, I ended up settling with the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ikea.com/us/en/catalog/products/40360217/&quot;&gt;IKEA Rallen&lt;/a&gt; integrated charger. I drilled a hole in my desk, fit it in, and have used it every night since. While I plan to write something up about this later in the week, the gist of it is: It’s about as fast as the charger that ships with the iPhone, which is much slower than the super-fast iPad chargers that I’ve been using recently, so it’s noticeably slower. This isn’t really a big deal in practice, because I tend to charge my phone overnight and it’s getting to 100% by the time I wake up either way, but if I need a quick top-up midday I’m still going to plug it in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;face-id&quot;&gt;Face ID&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s taken me this long to get to Face ID because honestly, in practice, I don’t really think about it. It works really well and you get used to it within a day or two. There were a couple of hiccups when I just woke up the first day, but it definitely seems to be learning because it hasn’t made that mistake since.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t have much more to say here, which is the highest praise that I can give this. It unlocks my phone every time, even right after a shower or a workout where Touch ID would fail previously. I’ve even tried it with a number of hoodies and winter jackets&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:6&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:6&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and it’s worked every time. I thought the thick, furry &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?safe=off&amp;amp;tbm=isch&amp;amp;source=hp&amp;amp;biw=980&amp;amp;bih=645&amp;amp;ei=UMUHWtfLOYnVmwGjy5DYCw&amp;amp;q=canada+goose+hood&amp;amp;oq=canada+goose+hood&amp;amp;gs_l=img.3..0l5j0i30k1j0i8i30k1l4.2295.4105.0.4284.19.18.0.0.0.0.174.2043.5j11.16.0....0...1..64.img..3.16.2041.0..35i39k1.0.htrkXeS-9h8&quot;&gt;Canada Goose hood&lt;/a&gt; might trip it but nope. Oh and unlocking apps that require authentication is super cool; you just wait a second for your phone to authenticate you, instead of actively reaching your thumb down to authenticate yourself. It’s the little things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-negatives&quot;&gt;The negatives&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There isn’t a lot  to complain about honestly, but I’ve definitely had a few minor inconveniences. For some reason, Face ID only works in portrait orientation, so if I’m lying down or at an angle I need to make sure that my phone is at that angle too, otherwise it won’t work. Also, when I wake up in the morning and grab my phone, I sometimes have a hard time keeping my eyes open while staring at the display so Face ID doesn’t work (though I probably shouldn’t be trying to use my phone if I can’t keep my eyes open). Those are both incredibly minor issues though. More pertinently, it’s been getting cold recently, and I’ve noticed that the display has been locking up in the for the first few minutes when it’s out in the cold. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.macrumors.com/2017/11/09/iphone-x-cold-weather-fix/&quot;&gt;Apple says that this is a software issue&lt;/a&gt; and that a fix should be coming out soon. That’s great to hear because if this were a hardware issue, it would be a massive failure. Boston has only been cold for a few days and this has already been a noticeable irritation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a couple more software issues that I have. The keyboard has been elevated to make for more convenient typing, which is good, but there’s a lot of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.macrumors.com/2017/11/06/iphone-x-owners-complain-keyboard/&quot;&gt;wasted space&lt;/a&gt; underneath. I’m sure this is just a version one problem, but I really wish that Apple would do &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt; with that space. Landscape support on this phone is also a big step back from the Plus-line of iPhones that I’ve grown accustomed to. I find myself almost never using it anymore, except to watch video, which is a real bummer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;looking-forward&quot;&gt;Looking forward&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s a lot more that I would like to cover (battery, camera, performance, the lack of a home button, etc.) but I’m already running way longer than intended. The short of it is that the end-to-end software and hardware experience of this iPhone feels much more complete than any before it. Between the responsiveness of the display and the more natural animations, I find myself drawn to it. In times where I would previously pick up my iPad to complete a task, I’m now doing it on the iPhone (including typing out the entire first draft of this post).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like I said at the top, I’ve had every iPhone since the iPhone 4. I’ve loved them all. If there was no iPhone X this year, I would’ve gotten the iPhone 8 Plus and I probably would’ve loved that too&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:7&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:7&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. However, I’ve never been as &lt;em&gt;delighted&lt;/em&gt; with a new iPhone as I am with this one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve heard people say that this phone gives them the same feeling that they had when experiencing the original iPhone. I never owned that phone, but it makes complete sense. The closest I’ve felt to this experience would be my original iPhone 4, but nothing else comes close. If you’re at all interested in this stuff (and I assume you are, otherwise why are you still here?) you should listen to &lt;a href=&quot;https://daringfireball.net/thetalkshow/2017/11/10/ep-206&quot;&gt;this week’s episode of &lt;em&gt;The Talk Show&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. It nails so much of what I’ve tried to express here. Between the inherent quirks of OLED displays and the first generation quirks of Face ID, this is the least ‘perfect’ iPhone in a long time; but everything about it feels so &lt;em&gt;cool&lt;/em&gt; that you don’t just forgive it, you embrace it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every Apple product is better than the one before it, that’s a given, but I can honestly say that this is hands-down my favorite experience with an Apple product yet. The torch has been handed over from the AirPods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Unlocked, 256 GB, AppleCare+, Sales Tax brings me to about $50 shy of $1,500. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;I flirted with the idea of the Apple Folio Case but after trying it out in the store, I found the front half too flimsy and not worth twice the price. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:3&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;In portrait, at least. Landscape is a whole other issue. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:3&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:4&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Bank Of America and &lt;a href=&quot;http://shiningparadigm.com/post/98821780002/next-review-and-giveaway&quot;&gt;Next&lt;/a&gt; are the only holdouts. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:4&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:5&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;In a roundabout way, the OLED display on iPhone X has made me appreciate the OLED display on Apple Watch even more. It never occurred to me how you can’t really tell where the screen ends and the bezel begins on the Watch before, but now I can’t unsee it. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:5&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:6&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;It’s getting to that time of year again… &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:6&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:7&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;The internals match the iPhone X and I would’ve gotten wireless charging to boot. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:7&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://thoughtsandstuff.net/iphone-x</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thoughtsandstuff.net/iphone-x</guid>
        
        
        <category>apple</category>
        
        <category>iphone</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Using Lyft on Apple Watch</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/lyft-pickup.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I mentioned in &lt;a href=&quot;https://thoughtsandstuff.net/cellular-watch&quot;&gt;my last post&lt;/a&gt; that I’d really like to try out Lyft on Apple Watch. At the time, I couldn’t get the app to launch&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, but I reached out to Lyft support and was promised that a fix was coming soon; sure enough, the app was updated just a few days later. I’ve had a few chances to try out Lyft on the Watch this week while my iPhone was dead&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and thought that I’d report on the collective experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, it works pretty well. Launching the app brings up a screen that shows me roughly how long it’ll take for a Lyft to get to me, and lets me request a ride to my current location. I can change the pickup location to either my Home or Work address (pre-filled in the Lyft app on iPhone), or I can specify a new address by voice. I was worried that I wouldn’t be able to request a ride with Apple Pay — I have no saved credit cards in either Lyft or Uber, and that prevented me from using Uber on Apple Watch the last time I tried — but there was a native interface for that and I was able to request the ride with no problems. Once your payment processes, it contacts nearby drivers and matches you with one. You can now see the ETA, an image of the car, and the license plate number. Scrolling down, you can see the name and a picture of your driver, and you have options to call or text them from the Watch. After the ride, I have the options to tip and rate my driver.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under most circumstances, this should work great. The first couple of times that I used the app, it did. I’ve had a number of (relatively minor) issues though that I’d like to touch on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I almost never use my current location as a pickup address for Lyft. It’s usually an estimate, and I fine-tune it to make sure the ride goes to the right place. The last time I tried to use Lyft on the Watch, it had the address as 350 Mass Ave., which was across the street from me. I figured I’d change it to 353 Mass Ave., not because I was being lazy but because we would be heading in that direction anyways and I wanted to make navigation easier. Siri recognized the address fine, and I thought everything was going alright, until the driver ‘arrived’ a few minutes later and called me. Lyft had taken him to that address in Boston, while I was in Cambridge. I asked him to cancel the ride, paid the fee, and I called another car. I suppose I’ll just have to stick to using current location while on the Watch, because the screen isn’t large enough for me to suggest a feasible solution&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:3&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the driver is on the way, the app gives me an ETA but I wish it’d show me where they are. Sometimes the ETA is wildly off, and I’d like to be able to see both where they are and which direction they’re coming from. The Maps app on the Watch handles this well by letting you swipe left during navigation to see a map, and I wish Lyft would adopt this. Don’t make it the primary view, but have the option around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, there’s currently no way to add a drop-off destination on the Watch. I didn’t think that this would be an issue, but I’ve had drivers accept my ride request and cancel shortly after on two (out of three) separate occasions. I imagine that’s why, because that never happens on iPhone. Given that I pretty much only call a Lyft on my Watch when my iPhone is dead and I’m trying to get home, I’d appreciate having the same &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/lyft-address.jpeg&quot;&gt;interface&lt;/a&gt; as pickups for drop-offs, so that I could quickly tap ‘Home’ and save having to have my driver plug it in himself. Having a drop-off address would also allow Lyft to give me an estimate of what my trip would cost at the time of booking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As it stands, the app is &lt;em&gt;good enough&lt;/em&gt;. It does everything that I would expect it to, but it doesn’t go above and beyond. I’d love to see any of the above features were added, though I’m not holding my breath on that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Ditto for Uber, but I gave up on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.engadget.com/2017/04/25/ubers-terrible-horrible-no-good-very-bad-2017/&quot;&gt;that mess&lt;/a&gt; a while ago. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Seriously, what is up with the battery life on iOS 11? An iPhone 7 Plus should not be dying this often midday. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:3&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;This is also why I’m not asking for features like switching between ride types (Line, Plus, etc.). &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:3&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 22 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://thoughtsandstuff.net/lyft-watch</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thoughtsandstuff.net/lyft-watch</guid>
        
        
        <category>apple</category>
        
        <category>watch</category>
        
        <category>lyft</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Positing a cellular Apple Watch for travel</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Sometime in early September, I was in a mall in Lisbon and my iPhone was dying. I decided to call an Uber back to the hotel (I don’t speak the language and didn’t feel comfortable without my phone). It was a little far away, and I anxiously watched the battery drain. Luckily, I managed to get in the car right as my phone died.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The incident stuck with me. Our phones are so important, &lt;em&gt;especially&lt;/em&gt; while away in a foreign country. Over the following few days, I mulled over the idea of an updated Apple Watch with LTE support. I wrote a full blog post and was getting ready to publish it, but one thing led to another and I never ended up doing so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the time since: Apple both announced and released the Series 3 Watch with LTE support, and I’ve been wearing one every day since. About three weeks in, I thought it’d be fun to check-in and see how it compares to what I hoped for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First and foremost, there’s one thing I need to get out of the way: &lt;strong&gt;The Apple Watch with LTE doesn’t roam.&lt;/strong&gt; It’s locked to the country where you bought it. There are &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.imore.com/how-roam-your-apple-watch-and-use-lte-data-foreign-country&quot;&gt;hacks&lt;/a&gt; to get it to work, but I use a cellular &lt;a href=&quot;https://thoughtsandstuff.net/project-fi&quot;&gt;Project Fi SIM&lt;/a&gt; when traveling internationally so this would have been a nonstarter. In the case that I described above, the LTE on my Watch would have been no additional help. However, there are plenty of times in Boston when my phone dies while I’m out and about, so this is still worth exploring&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s very rare that I’m out of the house without wearing headphones. In the event that my phone dies, I would like to be able to continue listening to music and podcasts. watchOS 4.0 smartly syncs a subset of playlists to the Watch overnight, and watchOS 4.1 (currently in beta) &lt;a href=&quot;https://9to5mac.com/2017/09/27/watchos-4-1-apple-music-streaming-radio/&quot;&gt;brings full Apple Music support&lt;/a&gt; to the device. Switching AirPods input from iPhone to Watch is seamless, too. Unfortunately, podcasts are a big miss on the Watch (and &lt;a href=&quot;https://marco.org/2017/09/24/what-watch-podcast-apps-need&quot;&gt;it doesn’t look likely&lt;/a&gt; that third-party apps are going to be able to plug that hole anytime soon).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my opinion, the Maps app is one of the most underrated features of the Apple Watch. It does a good job of surfacing potential destinations, handles navigation well (with the aid of haptics), and has fantastic public transport overviews. Alas, if my phone dies while I’m out in Boston, I’m confident that I can find my way home without needing Maps; but I’m almost excited to get lost in another state!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Boston, what I’m likely to do if my phone dies is check where the bus is. The MBTA runs notoriously behind schedule so I like checking where my transfer is before deciding whether I should get off the bus or stick it out a little more and walk the rest of the way. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/transit-bus-subway-times/id498151501?mt=8&amp;amp;uo=4&amp;amp;at=10l6nh&quot;&gt;Transit&lt;/a&gt; app on Apple Watch best surfaces this information, but unfortunately it doesn’t yet have LTE support&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. In the meantime, I’ve been using &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/citymapper-transit-navigation/id469463298?mt=8&amp;amp;uo=4&amp;amp;at=10l6nh&quot;&gt;Citymapper&lt;/a&gt; for this. Their Watch app does a lot more than Transit’s so it takes a couple of extra taps to find what I want, but it gets the job done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alternately, if my phone’s dead, I’m likely to call a Lyft home — especially if it’s later in the day. While I read that &lt;a href=&quot;http://time.com/4956444/apple-watch-3-review/&quot;&gt;Lyft and Uber have been updated with LTE support&lt;/a&gt;, I can’t seem to get either app to launch (with or without a connection to my iPhone). I contacted Lyft support and, after some troubleshooting, they informed me that it’s a known issue. Hopefully it gets resolved soon because this is something I’d really like to try out.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:3&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; (&lt;strong&gt;UPDATE:&lt;/strong&gt; The app got updated, and &lt;a href=&quot;/lyft-watch&quot;&gt;I tried it out&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, while I probably won’t need to translate anything on my Watch anytime soon (because it doesn’t roam), I was disappointed to find out that Siri on the Watch can’t handle translations. Siri on iOS 11 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.macrumors.com/how-to/siri-translation-ios-11/&quot;&gt;gained the ability&lt;/a&gt; to translate to a few select languages, but asking Siri on watchOS 4 the same query tells me to ‘Continue on iPhone.’ Fortunately, &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/itranslate-translator/id288113403?mt=8&amp;amp;uo=4&amp;amp;at=10l6nh&quot;&gt;iTranslate&lt;/a&gt; has a fantastic watchOS app that supports many more languages than Siri, &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; works over LTE.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Putting it all together, it’s remarkable to me how much the Watch can do independent of iPhone already. In an emergency, I could contact a friend or family,    find my way home, and continue listening to music. This is, of course, in addition to what the Watch could already do: Store boarding passes and more in Wallet, and pay for things with Apple Pay&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:4&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:4&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I look forward to being able to stream Apple Music in the near future. With 3rd-party apps (slowly) being updated to make them independent, it’s a good time to buy an Apple Watch. Hopefully a Podcasts app isn’t far behind, though I fear Apple might push that back until watchOS 5 at the earliest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;It actually happens surprisingly often. iOS 11 has been a nightmare for my battery life. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;I’ve contacted the developers and it’s something that they’re working on. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:3&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;I remember trying to use the Uber app on Apple Watch back when it first came out, and it didn’t work because I only have Apple Pay tied to my account (no Credit Card). The Uber extension in Maps still doesn’t work for me for that reason, but Lyft does, so I’m curious to see if it works on the Watch too. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:3&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:4&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;I know Apple Pay is almost universally accepted in developed countries outside the United States, but it’s starting to feel that way here in Boston/Cambridge too. Most ATMs, vending machines, liquor and grocery stores, etc. in the area have started accepting it (often without even realizing that they do). &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:4&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://thoughtsandstuff.net/cellular-watch</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thoughtsandstuff.net/cellular-watch</guid>
        
        
        <category>apple</category>
        
        <category>watch</category>
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Equation Group Breach</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Report on the breach of The Equation Group by The Shadow Brokers, and a look at the &lt;em&gt;EXTRABACON&lt;/em&gt; exploit. Prepared by &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Alexander Oleinik, Brian Roach, Jennifer Tsui, and Karan Varindani&lt;/code&gt; for &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Boston University, CS558 Network Security (February 2017)&lt;/code&gt;. This work was done without any outside collaboration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In August of 2016, a hacking &amp;amp; possible political interest group codenamed The Shadow Brokers breached The Equation Group, likely a subdivision of the NSA’s elite cybersecurity unit, and gained a collection of exploits used to predominantly target network hardware, such as the Cisco ASA series firewalls. The Shadow Brokers attempted to auction off these exploits, and released a small sample of them to prove their authenticity. One such sample was named &lt;em&gt;EXTRABACON&lt;/em&gt;, which allows an adversary to disable password authentication on Cisco ASA series firewalls through an SNMP request, and then allows the adversary to enter and ‘own’ the firewall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will discuss the parties involved in this breach, the motivations of the Shadow Brokers, the media coverage surrounding the event, and the &lt;em&gt;EXTRABACON&lt;/em&gt; exploit (and how to prevent it).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-players&quot;&gt;The Players&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The two players involved in this event were The Shadow Brokers and The Equation Group. They are both unknown threat actors, but there are suspicions as to their identities. The Equation Group was discovered by Kaspersky Labs in February 2015.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; They claimed that the group was tied to Stuxnet and Flame, which were both associated with cyberattacks launched by the United States.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Some think that the group is associated with the NSA. Nicholas Weaver in particular claimed that “Because of the sheer volume and quality, it is overwhelmingly likely that this data is authentic, and it does not appear to be information taken from compromised targets. Instead, the exploits, binaries with help strings, server configuration scripts, 5 separate versions of one implant framework, and all sort of other features indicate that this is analyst-side code—the kind that probably never leaves the NSA.”&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:3&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Some think that the Equation Group is a part of the Tailored Access Operations (TAO) division, which is a cyber-warfare intelligence-gathering subunit of the NSA.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:4&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:4&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:5&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:5&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; David Sanger of the New York Times said, “According to these experts, the coding resembled a series of ‘products’ developed inside the NSA’s highly classified Tailored Access Operations unit, some of which were described in general terms in documents stolen three years ago by Edward J. Snowden, the former NSA contractor now living in Russia.” While the Snowden documents confirmed that some of the exploits the Equation Group had were indeed once the property of the NSA, many are still reluctant to say that the Equation Group is actually the NSA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Shadow Brokers are an anonymous party who were selling exploits gained from supposedly breaching the Equation Group, and they were being sold for 1 million bitcoins (approximately 500 million USD at time of sale). Some believe that the Shadow Brokers are a foreign political adversary, such as Snowden, who believes that they are the Russian Government.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:6&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:6&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Others believe that it could be an NSA insider, such as the federal cybersecurity contractor Harold T. Martin III, who was found to have smuggled several terabytes of classified information from the NSA.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:7&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:7&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, an argument is made that the statements made by the Shadow Brokers were written by a native English speaker attempting to fake non native speech patterns, which would cast doubt on Snowden’s theory.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:8&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:8&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Ultimately, the identify of both The Equation Group and The Shadow Brokers is not known. In regards to The Shadow Brokers, their true identity likely will not be discovered as they have since ceased operation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;motivation-of-the-shadow-brokers&quot;&gt;Motivation of The Shadow Brokers&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many individuals thought the timing with which The Shadow Brokers leaked the exploits to be highly coincidental; around the same time, DNC emails were being leaked by a person named Guccifer 2.0.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:9&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:9&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Edward Snowden has claimed the following about the Equation Group hack on Twitter (with the assumption that the Russian government is behind the Shadow Brokers):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“This leak is likely a warning that someone can prove US responsibility for any attacks that originated from this malware server. That could have significant foreign policy consequences. Particularly if any of those operations targeted US allies, particularly if any of those operations targeted elections. Accordingly, this may be an effort to influence the calculus of decision-makers wondering how sharply to respond to the DNC hacks. TL;DR: This leak looks like a somebody sending a message that an escalation in the attribution game could get messy fast.”&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:10&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:10&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;10&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To summarize, Snowden believes that the Russian government was sending a warning to the US; If the US were to publicly blame Russia for the DNC, “it will retaliate by leaking potentially damaging information about US cyber-intelligence operations to the world.”&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:11&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:11&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;11&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; However, this may have simply been a ‘hack back’; In the past, the Shadow Brokers could have been hacked by The Equation Group, so they figured they would hack them back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;press-coverage&quot;&gt;Press Coverage&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The breach of the Equation Group by The Shadow Brokers caught the attention of the mainstream media because of the likely possibility that the NSA’s exploits had been stolen and partially released to the public. The obvious concern that a federal agency, tasked with upholding national security, had been compromised gave way to a plethora of headlines, from major to smaller news outlets alike. &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Business Insider&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;The Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;, and more covered the topic, with headlines like “‘Shadow Brokers’ Leak Raises Alarming Question: Was the NSA Hacked?” from &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt;, and “‘Shadow Brokers’ claim to have hacked an NSA-linked elite computer security unit” from &lt;em&gt;Business Insider&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:12&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:12&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;12&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:13&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:13&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;13&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; In addition to attention from the mainstream media, the technical media covered how this attack may have transpired, as well as detailing how the leaked exploits operated and the threats they posed to the public. &lt;em&gt;The Hacker News&lt;/em&gt; detailed the authenticity of the leak, specifically &lt;em&gt;EXTRABACON&lt;/em&gt;, and confirmed that Cisco was aware of the holes in its ASA firewall security and was patching the issue.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:14&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:14&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;14&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Additionally, sources like &lt;em&gt;Ars Techinca&lt;/em&gt; covered the event from a technical perspective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-extrabacon-exploit&quot;&gt;The &lt;em&gt;EXTRABACON&lt;/em&gt; Exploit&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While The Shadow Brokers were asking for 1 million bitcoins to release all the exploits, they shared an archive containing several Equation Group tools for free in as a proof-of-concept. One of these tools was the &lt;em&gt;EXTRABACON&lt;/em&gt; exploit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-it-works&quot;&gt;How it works&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;EXTRABACON&lt;/em&gt; (EXBA) leverages a buffer overflow in Cisco’s SNMP implementation on the Adaptive Security Appliance (ASA) software. According to Cisco, “An exploit could allow the attacker to execute arbitrary code and obtain full control of the system or to cause a reload of the affected system”.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:15&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:15&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;15&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Firewalls are commonly positioned at the border of a network and handle traffic flowing in and out of the network. Cisco’s ASA performs functions at every layer in the OSI network model. The ASAs are able to process 40Gbps of traffic and can handle 15000 simultaneous VPN connections.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:16&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:16&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;16&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; A compromise can entail a catastrophic compromise of privacy and network integrity affecting many connections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ASA provides many services to facilitate network administration. EXBA targets two of these - Simple Network Management Protocol (SNMP) and Secure Shell (SSH). SNMP is generally run on UDP port 161 and is widely used for collecting and monitoring hardware statistics. An SNMP client sends a request containing an Object Identifier (OID) and a community string to the server and receives a response containing a value corresponding to the OID. The community string acts as a very basic form of security - in SNMP versions prior to 3, it is transmitted as plaintext and susceptible to man-in-the-middle (MITM) attacks.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:17&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:17&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;17&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; SNMP security is widely neglected as many administrators wrongfully assume that no harm can be done to the hardware with access to read-only SNMP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SSH, on the other hand, is the primary protocol used by network engineers to perform configuration and administration tasks on hardware.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:18&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:18&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;18&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; The SSH server on ASAs supports several ciphersuites such as DHE-RSA-AES128-SHA and DES-CBC3-SHA.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:19&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:19&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;19&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Admins generally understand the importance of using strong keys/passwords to prevent unauthorized access via SSH.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EXBA assumes that the attacker has obtained the SNMP community string by MITM, or guessing a common default such “public”. Additionally the attacker must have access to the ASA on an SNMP-enabled interface. EXBA works by sending an SNMP request with OID 1.3.6.1.2.1.1.1.0, to which the firewall responds with its version string. With this information, EXBA crafts and sends a malicious version-specific OID. Upon processing this OID, a buffer overflow occurs on the ASA. The OID is constructed in such a way that when the overflow occurs, the ASA calls sys_mprotect to disable protection on the memory address responsible for enabling/disabling password authentication. The contents of the address are changed to disable authentication before returning to a safe address.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the attack executed, SSH connections are no longer authenticated and the attacker has access to install persistent malware, tamper with configuration and eavesdrop on the firewall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/extrabacon-attack.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;The attack on the ASA's SNMP handler occurs within one request&quot; title=&quot;EXTRABACON Attack&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-targets&quot;&gt;The targets&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Shadow Brokers uploaded encrypted archives of malware to several file-sharing services including mega.co.nz and Yandex disk. They provided decryption keys for one “sample archive” containing exploits including &lt;em&gt;BANANAUSURPER&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;BLATSTING&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;EXTRABACON&lt;/em&gt;. All of these exploits target enterprise firewalls. Most internet traffic passes through one of these devices at the business border, or ISP level. Due to the throughput, routing, and packet inspection capabilities of enterprise firewalls, a single compromise has potential to affect tens of thousands of users.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:20&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:20&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;20&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; The exploits target a wide range of hardware manufacturers. For example, &lt;em&gt;ELIGIBLEBOMBSHELL&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;ELIGIBLECANDIDATE&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;ELIGIBLECONTESTANT&lt;/em&gt; all target TOPSEC firewalls. This manufacturer’s products are not used much outside of China where its hardware has supported high-profile clients such as spacecraft, the 2008 Olympic Games, and Shenzhen University.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;preventing-extrabacon-attacks&quot;&gt;Preventing &lt;em&gt;EXTRABACON&lt;/em&gt; attacks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a few ways to prevent EXTRABACON attacks:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, install the latest patch update from CISCO. Previously compromised hardware might still be susceptible if the attacker installed a rootkit while he had access to the system, but fresh installs should be secure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Administrators should also limit SSH and SNMP interfaces. Preventing external access to the firewall would make sure attackers would have to have a local hardware connection to compromise the system by blocking remote access to certain ports on the network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, update to SNMP version 3 or later. This version, released in 2005, brings Triple DES Encrypted Authentication.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:21&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:21&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;21&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Triple DES (3-DES) is defined as a symmetric-key block cipher which applies the Data Encryption Standard (DES) cipher algorithm three times to each data block.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:22&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:22&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;22&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, using Strong Authentication in general is always helpful and good practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://usa.kaspersky.com/about-us/press-center/press-releases/2015/kaspersky-lab-discovers-equation-group-crown-creator-cyber-espi&quot;&gt;Kaspersky&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://usa.kaspersky.com/about-us/press-center/press-releases/2015/kaspersky-lab-discovers-equation-group-crown-creator-cyber-espi&quot;&gt;Kaspersky&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:3&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lawfareblog.com/very-bad-monday-nsa-0&quot;&gt;Lawfare&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:3&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:4&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tailored_Access_Operations&quot;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:4&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:5&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/security/2016/08/hints-suggest-an-insider-helped-the-nsa-equation-group-hacking-tools-leak/&quot;&gt;ArsTechnica&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:5&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:6&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.businessinsider.com/edward-snowden-shadow-brokers-russia-leaked-nsa-equation-group-files-warning-dnc-hacking-2016-8?r=DE&amp;amp;IR=T&quot;&gt;BusinessInsider&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:6&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:7&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2016/10/20/us/harold-martin-nsa.html&quot;&gt;NYTimes&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:7&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:8&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://taia.global/2016/08/shadowbroker-is-a-native-english-speaker-trying-to-appear-non-native/&quot;&gt;taia.global &lt;em&gt;(deprecated)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:8&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:9&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/view/articles/2017-01-13/cyberwar-has-gone-public-and-that-s-dangerous&quot;&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:9&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:10&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2016/08/snowden-speculates-leak-of-nsa-spying-tools-is-tied-to-russian-dnc-hack/&quot;&gt;ArsTechnica&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:10&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:11&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.businessinsider.com/edward-snowden-shadow-brokers-russia-leaked-nsa-equation-group-files-warning-dnc-hacking-2016-8?r=DE&amp;amp;IR=T&quot;&gt;BusinessInsider&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:11&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:12&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2016/08/17/us/shadow-brokers-leak-raises-alarming-question-was-the-nsa-hacked.html?_r=3&quot;&gt;NYTimes&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:12&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:13&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.businessinsider.com/shadow-brokers-claims-to-hack-equation-group-group-linked-to-nsa-2016-8&quot;&gt;BusinessInsider&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:13&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:14&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thehackernews.com/2016/08/nsa-hack-exploit.html&quot;&gt;HackerNews&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:14&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:15&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20160817-asa-snmp&quot;&gt;Cisco&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:15&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:16&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cisco.com/c/en_ca/products/security/asa-5500-series-next-generation-firewalls/models-comparison.html\#tab-c&quot;&gt;Cisco&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:16&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:17&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ietf.org/rfc/rfc1157.txt&quot;&gt;Internet Engineering Task Force (IETF)&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:17&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:18&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc4253&quot;&gt;Internet Engineering Task Force (IETF)&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:18&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:19&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/td/docs/security/asa/asa-command-reference/S/cmdref3/s16.html&quot;&gt;Cisco&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:19&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:20&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.topsec.com.cn/english/about_us.html&quot;&gt;Topsec&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:20&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:21&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/td/docs/ios/12_4t/12_4t2/snmpv3ae.html&quot;&gt;Cisco&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:21&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:22&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Triple_DES&quot;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:22&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://thoughtsandstuff.net/equation</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thoughtsandstuff.net/equation</guid>
        
        
        <category>education</category>
        
        <category>security</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Spending time with Apple's TV app</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Apple brought its new TV app to iOS and Apple TV devices with iOS 10.2 and tvOS 10.1 respectively almost a month ago, and I’ve been using it extensively since. Josh Centers has a good article on &lt;a href=&quot;http://tidbits.com/article/16949&quot;&gt;how it works&lt;/a&gt; over on TidBITS for those unaware, including information on the complementary Single Sign-On feature. Joe Steel also expressed &lt;a href=&quot;http://joe-steel.com/2016-12-13-First-Impressions-of-TV-the-App.html&quot;&gt;similar sentiments&lt;/a&gt; last month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-app&quot;&gt;The app&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’d like to touch on the app experience itself before discussing content, which is the crux of this post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The TV app is broken down into four tabs: &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Library&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Watch Now&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Store&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Search&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Library&lt;/code&gt; tab of the app shows me my purchased Movies and TV Shows, sorted by Most Recent first. It replaces the old Videos app. I don’t understand why this is the first tab on iOS but the second on tvOS. I almost never launch the app with the intention of going here, and I don’t get the inconsistency. I’d much rather the ordering was maintained, with &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Watch Now&lt;/code&gt; being the first tab on both platforms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Watch Now&lt;/code&gt; is my biggest draw to the TV app, yet also the part of the app that I feel needs the most work. It has an &lt;em&gt;Up Next&lt;/em&gt; section on top, which acts as a queue of content added from a number of sources (manually or automatically). I understand that Apple is trying to make it as invisible as possible but it feels a step too far right now. Currently, when you search for something in the TV app and choose to play it, it opens up in its parent app (Hulu, ABC, etc.) and the TV app automatically starts keeping track of it in &lt;em&gt;Up Next&lt;/em&gt;. You can remove something from the queue by long pressing it and tapping ‘Remove from Up Next’ on iOS or tvOS. However, there’s no way to mark an individual episode as played or get a list of your currently tracked shows. When I watch a new episode of a show live on cable TV, I have to play the episode again in the app and scrub to the end to get it to mark as watched and remove it from the queue. I’d like to see Apple do more here. Underneath &lt;em&gt;Up Next&lt;/em&gt; is a discovery section that presents content I have access to watch in the TV app. I’ve found this to be pretty useful, but I wish it was aware of shows that I’m already watching to reduce redundancy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Store&lt;/code&gt; tab shows me which apps have added support  for the TV app, and new releases on iTunes. I wish it differentiated the apps that I’ve already authorized from the list in some way (maybe grey them out or add a check mark). Apps that I’ve authorized from this list will populate the discovery sections of the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Watch Now&lt;/code&gt; tab.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last tab is &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Search&lt;/code&gt;, which is very cool. Like Universal Search on the Apple TV, it searches a bunch of supported apps (included Netflix, which is supported in &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Search&lt;/code&gt; but not &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Watch Now&lt;/code&gt;) and lets me know what’s available and where. For example, searching for &lt;em&gt;Bob’s Burgers&lt;/em&gt; tells me that it’s available on Hulu, FOX NOW, Netflix, iTunes, and TBS. I can then jump through the list of seasons and see where each episode is available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-content&quot;&gt;The content&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have access to Hulu, Netflix, and Amazon Prime Video, in addition to paying for cable TV through Comcast Xfinity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently, most of what I’m able to watch in the TV app is shows available in Hulu. To be specific, that’s &lt;em&gt;Designated Survivor&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Fresh Off the Boat&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Modern Family&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;The Goldbergs&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Bob’s Burgers&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. I could watch some of these shows (like &lt;em&gt;Bob’s Burgers&lt;/em&gt;) in their network’s app (FOX NOW) using my cable login, but I prefer to watch them ad-free in Hulu. The TV app remembers this preference and doesn’t ask me where I want to watch new episodes every week. I buy and rent movies from the iTunes Store fairly often and it’s great to have those automatically show up in the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Watch Now&lt;/code&gt; tab, too. Lastly, I love being able to search for movies and TV shows and adding them to &lt;em&gt;Up Next&lt;/em&gt; to watch later. Even if I can’t watch what I add in the TV app itself, I can still add it to help me keep track of what I want to watch. For example, I currently have the movie &lt;em&gt;Sully&lt;/em&gt; in my Up Next queue. When I’m ready to watch it, I can select it and see where it’s available for me to watch (currently only buy/rent from iTunes).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bigger story here though is with the content that I &lt;em&gt;can’t&lt;/em&gt; watch in the TV app. &lt;em&gt;Black Mirror&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Halt and Catch Fire&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Mr Robot&lt;/em&gt;, and many more shows are available to me on Netflix but I can’t keep track of my progress in the Watch Now tab&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. &lt;em&gt;The Grand Tour&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;The Man in the High Castle&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;24&lt;/em&gt; are available in Amazon Prime Video but not the TV app. And, unlike with Netflix, these shows don’t even appear in Search results so I can’t even tell if I have access to them (and other Amazon content) without doing a second search in the Amazon Prime Video app. Most inexplicable to me though is HBO. I don’t pay for HBO NOW, HBO’s standalone video service, because I pay for cable and thus have access to HBO GO, which has the same content but lets me watch it by signing in with my cable provider. For some reason, HBO has decided to make HBO NOW compatible with the TV app but not HBO GO. So when I search for movies/shows and see that they’re available on HBO NOW, I have to leave the TV app, switch over to HBO GO, and find them there. I also can’t keep track of shows I’m currently watching (like &lt;em&gt;Westworld&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Game of Thrones&lt;/em&gt;) in the TV app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HBO isn’t alone though - other networks like USA haven’t updated their apps to add TV support either. And not only does that frustrate me, but I find it to be cause for concern. Well over a year since the release of iOS 9, most of these apps don’t support fundamental iPad Pro technologies like Split View and Picture in Picture. Hell, I can’t even think of a single network app that supports the larger iPad Pro’s native resolution. What hope is there that they’ll add in support for the TV app — a feature that’s received very little media attention so far — anytime soon?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While there’s a fair amount of what I watch available in the TV app right now, I’m still watching a lot of TV elsewhere. There’s also a lot of TV that I &lt;em&gt;want&lt;/em&gt; to start watching, but I haven’t because it’s not supported in the TV app right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think that sums up how I feel about Apple’s latest TV offering: It removes so much minor irritation and is leaps and bounds better to navigate than any other individual app out there, but it doesn’t have nearly enough support from networks and other content providers right now, and it’ll ultimately fail without them. It’s so convenient that I’m actively holding out on watching things that aren’t supported in it right now, but without Hulu alone, this app would be next to useless to me. If Apple could get Netflix, Amazon Prime Video, and a few big networks (HBO GO and USA in particular for me) on board, it’d become infinitely more useful. And I do think that Apple has to go get these deals because I have little reason to believe that the networks will do it themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t talk about Single Sign-On but there are parallels there: It’s supported by very few TV Providers and similarly few network apps. Comcast Xfinity doesn’t support it so I haven’t had a chance to try it out. Given that &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/xfinity-tv/id731629156?mt=8&amp;amp;uo=4&amp;amp;at=10l6nh&quot;&gt;Xfinity’s TV app&lt;/a&gt; is a great iOS citizen&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:3&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, I’m hopeful that this’ll get added soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;updates&quot;&gt;Updates&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jan 17: &lt;a href=&quot;http://appleinsider.com/articles/17/01/18/apple-tv-iphone-ipad-gain-ability-to-play-netflix-movies-directly-in-tv-app&quot;&gt;Netflix adds ability to play content directly in TV app&lt;/a&gt;. Now, when you search for something in the TV app, you can see if it’s available on Netflix and playing it will immediately start playback in the Netflix app. However, Netflix still doesn’t let you track what you’re watching in &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Up Next&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jan 26: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.macrumors.com/2017/01/26/hbo-go-single-sign-on-tv-app/&quot;&gt;HBO GO adds support for Single Sign-On and TV app&lt;/a&gt;. This was a really big one for me. While I &lt;em&gt;still&lt;/em&gt; can’t use Single Sign-On with Comcast Xfinity, having HBO accessible in &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Search&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Watch Next&lt;/code&gt; has already been great. I’m still baffled it took so long (especially since HBO NOW has had this since day one) but that’s one less bastion&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:4&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:4&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; left to fall.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Don’t judge me. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;This is doubly frustrating because, as I mentioned earlier, I can search for Netflix shows in the TV app and it’ll open the movie/episode in the Netflix app; it just doesn’t keep track of progress in &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Watch Now&lt;/code&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:3&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;It supports the iPad Pro’s native resolution, Split View, and Picture in Picture - but not AirPlay. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:3&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:4&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Netflix and Amazon Prime Video remain, for those keeping track. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:4&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://thoughtsandstuff.net/tv-app</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thoughtsandstuff.net/tv-app</guid>
        
        
        <category>apple</category>
        
        <category>tv</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Traveling with AirPods</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/airpods.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apple’s AirPods were finally released to the public on Monday, and I managed to grab a pair at launch. I’ve been using them quite a bit over the last couple of days and I abslolutely love them. Right off the bat, I’ll say that this is my second-favorite new Apple product since 2013, behind only the Pencil.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, if there’s one thing I’ve learned over the years, it’s that nothing puts your tech through its paces quite like long-haul travel. And as luck would have it, I was making one such trip just two days after getting the AirPods. So, how did they fare? (Spoiler: &lt;em&gt;outstandingly&lt;/em&gt; well).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-setting&quot;&gt;The Setting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was scheduled to fly from Boston to Accra via Toronto and Istanbul, with 2 and 7 hour transits respectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Boston, my flight was heavily delayed, so I ended up spending 4 hours at the gate before boarding. I wore the AirPods pretty much throughout that time, and for most of the 90 minute flight to Toronto. My transit time in Toronto was cut to naught because of the delay, and then it was time for the main event: a 9 hour transatlantic flight to Istanbul. I then spent 6 hours in the Turkish Airlines lounge at Ataturk Airport, before boarding my final 7 hour flight to Accra.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Usually when I make this trip&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, my Beats Studio Wireless don’t leave my neck from the time I leave home until I fall asleep on the transatlantic flight, at which point I charge them for my transit in Istanbul and the last flight to Accra. But while I brought the Studios with me on this trip, at no point did I feel compelled to take them out of my bag.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;pros-and-cons&quot;&gt;Pros and Cons&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The AirPods are  &lt;em&gt;much&lt;/em&gt; smaller and lighter than my Beats, and I didn’t expect to appreciate that as much as I did. Being able to take them out and put them in my pocket was &lt;em&gt;so&lt;/em&gt; much more convenient than having to carry the Studios or leave them wrapped around my neck. I also felt like I could listen to use them for longer periods of time than the Studios, which are closed headphones and thus create a bunch of heat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the plane, being able to pull out one of the headphones and have my podcast/movie automatically pause so that I could interact with cabin crew (and resume when I put it back) was a very big plus. During meals, when I was talking to a member of cabin crew pretty often, I took out one headphone and put it back in the case, at which point the AirPods routed the sound from stereo to mono — a beautiful little detail. And don’t even get me started on the range. I was listening to a podcast on my iPad when I decided to visit the restroom, and I was actually able to get up, walk across the cabin, and use the facilities (with the iPad still at my seat) without the AirPods skipping a beat. I thought that was absolutely incredible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another big benefit to me was the easy switching between devices. Almost all the music I’d like to listen to on a flight is cached on my iPhone, but I have a bunch of Movies, TV Shows, and Podcasts downloaded on my iPad. There have been many times in the past where I’ve wanted to listen to music or watch a movie on a flight but didn’t because I just didn’t feel like switching devices. With the AirPods, I was free to switch as I pleased — and so I did. I understand that I can, and probably should, download my music to my iPad and have that be my all-in-one IFE system, but even if I did that I’d still need to switch between them because I obviously can’t lie down and use the 12.9” iPad Pro comfortably on a flight. I also understand that I could just switch between devices with wired headphones, but if that’s your solution, you clearly don’t know the bliss that is traveling with wireless headphones. It’s a complete game changer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was woken up for breakfast an hour before arriving in Istanbul, the AirPods had just over 50% of battery remaining (after 18 hours of use, and with 15 hours of travel remaining). I had slept for 5 hours on that flight, and I tend to travel with an Anker battery and a bunch of Lightning cables, so I could have charged the AirPods pretty easily, but I wanted to see if they could make it through the trip on a single charge. It turns out, I could. I used the AirPods for a few hours in the lounge, and then for a few more hours on the flight to watch a movie. And by the time I got home, 33 hours after leaving Boston, the case had about 5% remaining and the AirPods were fully charged (i.e. I still had about 5 hours of battery life remaining). That’s without me babying them in any way; at no point did I want to listen to something but didn’t because I was afraid that the battery will run out. That doesn’t happen with the Studios. Not only do I always have to find a few hours to charge it, but I have to carry around a micro-USB cable just for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what do we have here? Incredibly portable headphones with enough passthrough to use safely in a busy airport, and a very practical play/pause mechanism, with outstanding range and enough battery life to make it through almost two days of travel on a single charge. To me, that’s easily worth the asking price of $159. No question about that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But while there’s a lot to love about the AirPods, I’d be remiss if I didn’t mention the obvious downsides. I definitely missed having an in-line remote a lot on this trip for volume control. And while the AirPods have surprisingly good sound, it’s nothing compared to the Studios — especially when listening to music. Lastly, while these were particularly quiet flights (in no small part due to the magnificence of the Boeing 787 Dreamliner), I did miss the Active Noice Cancelation of the Studios at times. It wasn’t a big enough issue to make me get them out of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.awaytravel.com/luggage/carry-on/black&quot;&gt;my carry-on&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, but I did wish I had them during takeoff and landing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The AirPods were a huge hit on this trip. In the future, on short trips, I can’t see any reason for me to bring the Studios with me. However, on longer trips where I’d be packing them anyways for when I get to my destination, I can see myself leaving them in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.awaytravel.com/luggage/carry-on/black&quot;&gt;my carry-on&lt;/a&gt; to at least have that option. But long gone are the days of me walking through the terminal deaf to the world around me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I should also note that I spent most of this trip in airline lounges and a fairly spacious business class open suite. In economy, which is typically a lot louder and a lot more cramped, I might be more inclined to bring the Studios for their active noise cancellation and because I’m far less likely to lose them. My last flight to Accra ended up being in economy class and I woke up to pack the AirPods after dozing off because I was worried that someone might accidentally nudge them out of my ear while I was asleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Either way, the AirPods are undoubtedly my favorite new Apple product of the last couple of years, and I sense that they’re going to go on to completely change the way I listen to music. I’m sold on Apple’s idea of the future of wireless audio playback. Bring on W1 everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;I make a slight variant of this trip 6 times annually (3 round-trips), in addition to usual summer travel. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;You should check out &lt;a href=&quot;http://awaytravel.com&quot;&gt;Away&lt;/a&gt; if you travel with any sort of frequency. Their suitcases and carry-on bags are the best I’ve ever owned, and come with a no-hassle lifetime warranty. I genuinely love them. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://thoughtsandstuff.net/airpods</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thoughtsandstuff.net/airpods</guid>
        
        
        <category>apple</category>
        
        <category>airpods</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Using Project Fi with iOS</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/project-fi.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-project-fi&quot;&gt;What is &lt;em&gt;Project Fi&lt;/em&gt;?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you haven’t heard of Google’s &lt;em&gt;Project Fi&lt;/em&gt; network before, you might want to check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://fi.google.com/about/&quot;&gt;its About page&lt;/a&gt; before reading the rest of this but the gist of it is as follows: It’s a cell carrier owned by Google where you pay $20 per month for unlimited domestic talk and text, unlimited international texts, and the ability to use your phone as a Wi-Fi hotspot. Data costs $10 per GB and is pro-rated (so if you use 2.5 GB, you pay $25), and that pricing applies in over 135 countries(!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest caveat as an iPhone user (and generally as someone heavily into Apple’s ecosystem) is that officially, as of the time of writing, &lt;em&gt;Project Fi&lt;/em&gt; only works on three Android phones: the Nexus 6P, Nexus 5X, and Nexus 6. Google says that this is because “these devices are the first smartphones that support our network of networks.” However, if you would like to enroll in &lt;em&gt;Project Fi&lt;/em&gt;  and don’t have a supported phone, Google will sell you a Nexus 5X or a Nexus 6P for up to $150 off of the retail price. You can also request up to eight data-only SIMs for free with your plan. Together, that’s where things get interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do a lot of international travel every year. In 2016 alone, I’ve had trips and transits in over 20 different cities across 9 different countries. Unsurprisingly, traditional carriers don’t make it easy to use your phone abroad, with AT&amp;amp;T charging $40 for 200 MB in a limited set of countries (a couple of the ones I visited this year weren’t included) so, as you can imagine, &lt;em&gt;Project Fi&lt;/em&gt; piqued my interest early on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;getting-started&quot;&gt;Getting started&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ordered a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/LG-Nexus-5X-Unlocked-Smartphone/dp/B0178GE4FU&quot;&gt;Nexus 5X&lt;/a&gt; for $199 and a few data-only SIMs, and decided to put them to the test in a little trip that I’m taking right now.  The phone itself is fine to look at but, and I was happy getting it just to (finally) have a decent Android phone to play with, but I really just got it to activate the service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I currently have data-only SIMs in my iPhone 6S Plus, 9.7-inch iPad Pro, and 12.9-inch iPad Pro. After inserting the SIM card, I had to go to &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Settings &amp;gt; Cellular&lt;/code&gt; to turn on Data Roaming (and make sure LTE was enabled), and then go to &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Cellular Data Options&lt;/code&gt; to change the Cellular Data APN to ‘h2g2’ on each device in order to make &lt;em&gt;Project Fi&lt;/em&gt; work on iOS. That’s all there is to setting it up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tests-and-results&quot;&gt;Tests and Results&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I haven’t had a chance to test out &lt;em&gt;Project Fi&lt;/em&gt; in the United States, and I’ll probably update this list with more results as I keep traveling, but here’s what I have so far:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Istanbul: &lt;em&gt;Turkcell&lt;/em&gt; LTE, 2 Mbps in the airport&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rome: &lt;em&gt;TIM&lt;/em&gt; LTE, 18 Mbps in the city&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Barcelona: &lt;em&gt;movistar&lt;/em&gt; LTE, 20 Mbps in the airport&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These tests were taken on all three aforementioned iOS devices through Netflix’s &lt;a href=&quot;fast.com&quot;&gt;Fast.com&lt;/a&gt; with consistent results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I only mentioned the result from Rome above but I had similar results in Florence, Siena, Cinque Terre, Lucca, and other parts of Italy. (Speeds fluctuated between 3-18 Mbps but I consistently had usable LTE access.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-bottom-line&quot;&gt;The bottom line&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Google and_Project Fi_, I now have access to data when traveling &lt;a href=&quot;https://fi.google.com/coverage?u=0&quot;&gt;almost anywhere in the world&lt;/a&gt; for just $10 per GB. That’s  &lt;em&gt;incredible&lt;/em&gt; value — and I suspect that many international travelers would agree, even when factoring in the $20 per month for service and the $199 up-front for the Nexus 5X.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, after installing the Google Hangouts app on my iOS devices, I can now make (and receive) international calls and texts at a &lt;a href=&quot;https://fi.google.com/about/rates/&quot;&gt;low, variable per-minute rate&lt;/a&gt; through &lt;em&gt;Project Fi&lt;/em&gt; without having to carry the Nexus 5X with me. I don’t make or receive a lot of calls in general but it’s a nice added bonus, and I’ve already used it a few times on this trip. For example, I was able to call Istanbul from Rome for just 4¢ per minute even though the Nexus 5X was switched off. Rome to Barcelona was 1¢ per minute, Rome to the United States was free over Wi-Fi, and Rome to Accra would have cost me 23¢ per minute. (If I decided to use the Nexus 5X, all calls placed on it would have cost a fixed 20¢ per minute over the Fi Network, or the aforementioned rates over Wi-Fi.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wholeheartedly recommend &lt;em&gt;Project Fi&lt;/em&gt; — and I say that as someone who actively avoids Google for everything but Search. If Google could get it to work natively on iPhone, I would switch carriers in a heartbeat but I wouldn’t get my hopes up over that happening anytime soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;an-aside-on-the-97-inch-ipad-pro&quot;&gt;An aside on the 9.7-inch iPad Pro&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Apple released the 9.7-inch iPad Pro, there was a lot of discussion about the fact that it had a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cnet.com/news/apples-true-tone-display-whats-the-deal/&quot;&gt;True Tone display&lt;/a&gt; that its 12.9-inch sibling does not, but not a lot was made of the fact that it had both a SIM slot and an integrated Apple SIM. I found that interesting at the time because it essentially makes this the first dual-SIM iOS device.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I bought the iPad, I immediately added it to my AT&amp;amp;T Mobile Share plan using the integrated Apple SIM, remarking at how seamless the setup process was out of the box. After inserting the &lt;em&gt;Project Fi&lt;/em&gt; card in to the previously-empty SIM slot, I’m now remarking similar at how seamless the process of switching between carriers is. All I have to do is go to &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Settings &amp;gt; Cellular Data&lt;/code&gt; and tap one of the two options under ‘Choose a Data Plan.’ It couldn’t be easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I got to Istanbul, I only had a &lt;em&gt;Project Fi&lt;/em&gt; SIM card in the 9.7-inch iPad Pro (and in the Nexus 5X) because I didn’t want to bother switching a bunch of SIMs until I knew that the service worked. I mean, nobody likes switching SIM cards. It’s a terrible experience. I’m glad that with the smaller iPad Pro, this isn’t something that I’m going to have to do very often. I hope that this bleeds over to the 12.9-inch iPad Pro and becomes a mainstay feature, and that Apple doesn’t just kill the SIM card slot instead (and keep just the integrated Apple SIM around). Thankfully, the Apple SIM still has a long way to go to work in most countries around the world, so I think that the SIM card slot is safe — for the time being, at least.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also wonder how possible it would be to bring this to the iPhone. It’d be great if I could seamlessly switch between two SIM cards but, given that there would be phone numbers associated with the iPhone, it might be a little more complicated. Or maybe it’s not that complicated and I’m just overthinking this. I guess we’ll find out with the new iPhone in September. Until then, I now have this neat little &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/GPG2-Mobile-Safe-Case-travel/dp/B00GQ2HG6C/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1471319385&amp;amp;sr=8-1&amp;amp;keywords=Sim+card+holder&quot;&gt;SIM card holder&lt;/a&gt; with me in my backpack!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(I should add for the sake of completeness that the Apple SIM on iPad allows you to switch between carriers, and I could switch have switched from AT&amp;amp;T to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gigsky.com/&quot;&gt;GigSky&lt;/a&gt; — a pay-as-you-go international data carrier — while abroad, but I’d still need to come up with a solution on iPhone. Coupled with the fact that its &lt;a href=&quot;https://cl.ly/h8bP&quot;&gt;rates&lt;/a&gt; are largely unfavorable, &lt;em&gt;Project Fi&lt;/em&gt; still comes out as a much better option.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://thoughtsandstuff.net/project-fi</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thoughtsandstuff.net/project-fi</guid>
        
        
        <category>google</category>
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
        <category>project-fi</category>
        
        <category>apple</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
